nationalinsuranceindia.com 2019-08-18

# National Insurance Company Ltd |

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
Introduction
A privacy policy is a statement or a legal document (in privacy law) that discloses some or all of the
ways a party gathers, uses, discloses, and manages a customer or client's data. It fulfills a legal
requirement to protect a customer or client's privacy of data termed as Personally Identifiable
Information (PII).
This Privacy Policy sets forth the reasonable security practices and procedures adopted by NIC and
shall apply for use, disclosure and sharing of the Sensitive personal data or information (“personally
identifiable Information”) as provided by the customers to NIC website. This privacy policy is in
conjunction with the terms of use agreed by the customers while getting registered with NIC for
availing its services.
Definition
For the purpose of this document NIC shall mean National Insurance Company Limited.
The terms “<you>/<your>/user” are interchangeable with Customer / Customers.
Collecting Personal Information
PII for purposes of this Policy means information that identifies customer, for e.g. Customer’s Name,
Date of birth, Medical History/Records, Bank Account details or Credit Card or Debit Card details,
Biometric information, Phone number, Fax number or email address etc. PII provided by the
customers will be taken as it is and NIC will not be responsible for the authenticity of information
supplied by the customers. This PII which are provided/collected from the customers are solely for the
purposes connected with the terms of use which has been agreed upon by NIC with the customers to
provide various services by the Company as per applicability.
NIC may collect, store and use following kinds of information:
     i) Information provided by <you> to NIC at the time of registration in NIC website or otherwise
     ii) Information about <your> computer and about <your> visits to and use of this website
          (including <your> IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating
          system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths)
     iii) Information provided by <you> when completing <your> profile on NIC website or otherwise
          (including but not limited to name, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, medical history,
          relationship status, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details)
     iv) Information provided by <you> while subscribing to NIC’s email notifications and/or
          newsletters
     v) Information that <you> provide to us when using the services on NIC website, or that is
          generated in the course of the use of those services (including the timing, frequency and
          pattern of service use)
     vi) Information relating to any purchases that <you> make or any other transactions that <you>
          have entered into through NIC’s website or otherwise
1

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
     vii) Information that <you> post to our website for publication on the internet (including [<your>
           user name, <your> profile pictures and the content of <your> posts
     viii) Information contained in or relating to any communication that <you> have sent to NIC
           through website or otherwise (for e.g. email)
If <you> choose not to agree with the policy, <you> will not be entitled to use the Services as per the
terms of use.
Purpose
NIC needs this minimal information to operate and provide various services. NIC uses and discloses
Customers’ PII only as follows
     i)    To fulfill <your> requests for products and services offered and subscribed and accepted by
           <you>
     ii) To personalize NIC website for <you>
     iii) To deliver any administrative notices, alerts, advice and communications relevant to the usage
           of the Services or to administer the website and business
     iv) To share <your> information with NIC’s agents, group companies and other third parties in so
           far as required for joint marketing purposes and / or to other similar services to provide <you>
           various value added services
     v) Use the information for market research, project planning, troubleshooting problems,
           detecting and protecting against error, fraud or other criminal activity;
     vi) Disclose the information to the third-party contractors that provide services to NIC and are
           bound by these same privacy restrictions by dint of NDA
     vii) To provide third parties with statistical information about our users (but those third parties
           will not be able to identify any individual user from that information
     viii) To verify compliance with the terms and conditions governing the use of NIC’s website
           (including monitoring private messages sent through NIC’s website private messaging service)
     ix) To send email notifications, newsletter to <you> if the same have been specifically requested
           for
     x) To deal with enquiries and complaints made by the customers relating to NIC’s website
     xi) To enforce NIC’s Terms and Conditions regarding services offered
All such PII collected shall be retained as long as customer are having active account with NIC and till
such time as is required to avail various services or as may be required under the law. In case of
deactivation / termination of the account / services with us, the PII provided will no longer be used
and the same will also get deleted upon the expiry of the maximum tenure as may be prescribed under
the provisions of the law as applicable.
Financial transactions at NIC’s website are handled through Payment Services Provider [PSP], Axis
Bank Payment Gateway, Ingenico ePayments India Pvt Ltd (Formerly TechProcess Payment Services
Pvt Ltd) and BillDesk. Customer can review the provider's privacy policy at [URL]
https://www.axisbank.com/privacy-policy, http://www.techprocess.co.in/privacy-policy.php and
2

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
https://billdesk.com/privacy.htm. NIC will share information with payment services provider only to
the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments which customers make via website,
refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and
refunds.
Update Personal Information
NIC always encourages the customers to update their information as and when there are any changes.
Customers are also entitled to review the information provided to NIC so as to ensure that any PII or
sensitive personal data or information found to be inaccurate or deficient be corrected or amended
as feasible to the best of knowledge without any delay. NIC by no means shall be responsible for the
authenticity of the PII or sensitive personal data or information supplied / provided by the customers
at any point in time.
Sharing/Transfer/Disclosure of Personal Information (Domestic / International)
PII of the users will not be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties unless otherwise
stated at the time of collection or without the approval of the Customers as the case may be. However,
NIC might share, exchange and disclose information to affiliates and / or group companies, agents or
to any third party service provider to deliver the products and services to the customers in the manner
as agreed upon by them during the registration and buying the products / services.
NIC treats Customers’ PII as private and confidential and does not check, edit, or reveal it to any third
parties except where it is expressly agreed and where it believes in good faith that such action is
necessary to comply with the applicable legal and regulatory processes, or to protect and defend the
rights of other users or to enforce the terms of service. NIC may disclose PII where it is under legal
obligation to do so or where it is mandated / directed under law. NIC might transfer sensitive personal
data or information to another Indian or overseas body corporate that ensures the same level of data
protection that is adhered to by NIC as well if it is necessary for the performance of a lawful contract
between NIC and or any person on its behalf and customers or where customers have consented or
allowed the data transfer.
Customers to note the following:
     i)  NIC may disclose <your> PII to [any of our employees, officers, insurers, professional advisers,
         agents, suppliers or subcontractors] as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in the
         policy
     ii)  NIC may disclose <your> PII:
         (a)      To the extent that it is required to do so by law
         (b)      In connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings
         (c)      In order to establish, exercise or defend any legal rights (including providing
         information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk)
3

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
Unsolicited Information
Except where specifically agreed or necessary for operational or regulatory reasons, NIC will not send
any unsolicited information to customers. However, to help the customers to take full advantage of
the service offerings of NIC, customers will have the opportunity to indicate whether they would like
to "opt out" of receiving promotional and/or marketing information about other products, services
and offerings from NIC and/or any third parties etc. If the user does not opt out, then NIC may use any
email addresses of the customer to send occasional emails pertaining to the said information.
Customers can nevertheless unsubscribe from receipt of such emails by following instructions therein
or by communicating accordingly to NIC.
Retention of Personal Information
NIC shall not retain PII longer than the purpose for which it is required subject to provisions of any law
for the time being in force. The information so collected shall be used only for the purpose for which
it is collected.
Third Party Services: Users should also be aware that NIC may sometimes permit third parties to offer
subscription and/or registration-based services through its website. However NIC is and will not be
responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties and users should check the applicable
privacy policy of such party when providing PII. Further, NIC will also not be responsible if the
Customers do not get the benefits announced if any, by the third parties permitted to offer
subscription and registration based services on its site.
Use of Cookies
NIC web sites may use "cookies" (information stored on customer’s computer by their browser at NIC
request). "Cookies" is a term generally used for small text files a website can use to recognize repeat
users, facilitate the user's ongoing access to and use of the site, allow a site to track usage behavior
and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising etc.
Cookies themselves do not personally identify anyone in person, but they do identify the computer.
Generally cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user computer that has no meaning
outside the assigning site. Customers are being made aware that NIC cannot control the use of cookies
or the resulting information by advertisers or third parties hosting data on the Company website. If a
Customer does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure
in most browsers that allows the user to deny or accept the cookie feature.
Children
NIC’s websites are not intended for use by children and minors. Parents are requested to ensure that
PII is not provided by any minors in NIC website at any point in time.
Blocking IP Addresses
4

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
NIC uses the help of Internet Protocol ("IP") addresses to diagnose any problems with its server and
to administer its web site including by blocking certain addresses that it feels are inappropriately using
its website. IP addresses may be used to gather broad demographics information, such as browser
types, visitor's country, visiting frequency, operating systems, etc.
Data may be transferred upon change in control but only in accordance with this Policy
PII may be transferred to a third party as a result of a sale, acquisition, merger, reorganization or other
change in control. If the Company is sold, merged or transferred any part of our business, part of the
sale may include <your> PII.
Security of Data
NIC will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or
alteration of customers’ PII. All the PII provided by customers are stored on our secure (password- and
firewall-protected) servers. All electronic financial transactions entered into through NIC’s website/s
will be protected by encryption technology.
<You> acknowledge that the transmission of information over the internet is inherently insecure, and
NIC cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet. <you> are responsible for keeping
the password <you> use for accessing NIC website confidential; NIC will not ask <you> for <your>
password (except when <you> log in to our website).
NIC details
     i) This website is owned and operated by National Insurance Co. Ltd.
     ii) NIC is registered in India, under IRDAI Registration Number 58_ and CIN
          U10200WB1206GOI001713
     iii) NIC’s principal place of business is at National Insurance Co. Ltd., Head Office, 3 Middleton
          Street, Kolkata 700071
     iv) <You> can contact NIC:
          Chief Manager, CRM Department, Head Office,
          National Insurance Co. Ltd., VII Floor,
          Chhabil Das Towers, 6-A, Middleton Street,
          Kolkata - 700071, 033-22815483,__________
          Email: grievance@nic.co.in;
Links to Other Web Sites
This Privacy Policy does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. Those sites are
not governed by this Privacy Policy, and if <you> have questions about how a site uses your
information, <you> will need to check that site’s privacy statement.
5

National Insurance Company Ltd | Privacy Policy
Change in Privacy Policy
NIC reserves the right to change Privacy Policy at any time. Customers may note that this Privacy Policy
itself and any such change of policy will be effective from the date of posting on the site.
Grievances
In case of any grievances as regards misuse or processing of <your> PII in a time bound manner, please
contact Chief Manager, CRM Department, Head Office, National Insurance Co. Ltd., VII Floor, Chhabil
Das Towers, 6-A, Middleton Street, Kolkata - 700071, 033-22815483, or email at grievance@nic.co.in.
The Grievance Officer shall redress <your> grievances expeditiously usually not later than one month
from the date of receipt of grievance.
Disclaimer
In spite of its best efforts to protect the interest of its clients it is made clear that in the unlikely event
of any data theft or, misuse, NIC will not be liable in any way.
The policies uploaded in the website of NICL are illustrative in nature and the rights and liabilities of
the parties are to be governed strictly by the actual contract entered into and signed by the parties
thereto. The party intending to seek insurance cover from NICL, may at its option, pay extra premium
and get add-on coverage in respect of the particular insurance policy.
Feedback
NIC welcomes feedback regarding this Policy at website.administrator@nic.co.in. If at any time <you>
believe that NIC has not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please send <your> feedback and NIC shall
endeavor to resolve the same.
Some of the services, facilities mentioned above may not yet be available or may have been withdrawn
at the discretion of NIC.
6
